<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS875 | QuantumDA</title>
    <link>/category/cs875/</link>
      <atom:link href="/category/cs875/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CS875</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>CS875</title>
      <link>/category/cs875/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emergent Technology and Key Trend for Education in 2020</title>
      <link>/post/emergent-technology-and-key-trend-for-education-in-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/emergent-technology-and-key-trend-for-education-in-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The “Emerging Technologies &amp;amp; Practices and Influential Trends” document and mind map present an overview of the technologies and trends that will be shaping the practices and technologies used in the higher education community (2020 EDUCAUSE Horizon Report, 2020). This diagram and report show an interesting emergence of the use of Artificial Intelligence (AI)  technology in education related systems. The Educause information also presents the social trend of equity and fair practice for educational systems. This blog post will outline where AI is emerging and a driving force behind this emergence. The post will also present an example of a social trend that utilizes AI technology as the enabler with ethical treatment as the driving force.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://er.educause.edu/-/media/files/library/2020/3/2020_horizon_report_infographic.pdf?la=en&amp;hash=66854F48297FEB53724C25A93E7475355EE6D4E3&#34; title=&#34;Redirect to Image Source&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2020-04-24-emergent-technology-and-key-trend-for-education-in-2020_files/HorizonR2020infographic3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Infographic&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDUCAUSE Review is a registered trademark of EDUCAUSE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;aimachine-learning-technology&#34;&gt;AI/Machine Learning Technology&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Educause document and diagram expose AI and the subset of Machine Learning (ML) as an emerging technology for educational use in 2020 (2020 EDUCAUSE Horizon Report, 2020).  The Educause reports identifies the areas of learning management systems (LMS), library services, mobile products, student information systems (SISs) and automatic captioning systems as demonstrations of increasing ML activity. The ML activity is present in the capacity of automation within the previously identified areas (2020 EDUCAUSE Horizon Report, 2020).  Not surprising is the economical force behind the push for ML in automation, both as applied in the educational setting as well as in general organizations (Zeide, 2019). As ML can increase the effectiveness of automation through improved accuracy which in turn can increase the productivity of human activities for increase in organizational value (How AI, Machine Learning, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;social-trends&#34;&gt;Social Trends&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A great example of AI/ML in the educational space is the use of ML for the automation of captioning or transcription of audio and video files (Solís, 2019). This example of AI/ML application follows social trend as identified in the Educause diagram (2020 EDUCAUSE Horizon Report, 2020). This trend has a driving force of ethical treatment or fair use practice for students with disabilities (Solís, 2019).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2020 EDUCAUSE horizon report™: Teaching and learning edition. (2020, March 2). Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.educause.edu/horizon-report-2020&#34;&gt;https://www.educause.edu/horizon-report-2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How AI, Machine Learning &amp;amp; Automation Impact Business in 2018 &amp;amp; Beyond. (2017, December 11). Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tenfold.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-machine-learning-automation-will-impact-business-2018-beyond&#34;&gt;https://www.tenfold.com/artificial-intelligence/ai-machine-learning-automation-will-impact-business-2018-beyond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solís, C. (2019, December 15). &lt;i&gt;Home&lt;/i&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://doit.wp.txstate.edu/2019/08/09/tio-team-completes-assessment-of-ai-driven-transcription/&#34;&gt;https://doit.wp.txstate.edu/2019/08/09/tio-team-completes-assessment-of-ai-driven-transcription/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zeide, E. (2019, August 26). &lt;i&gt;Artificial intelligence in higher education: applications, promise and perils, and ethical questions &lt;/i&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://er.educause.edu/articles/2019/8/artificial-intelligence-in-higher-education-applications-promise-and-perils-and-ethical-questions&#34;&gt;https://er.educause.edu/articles/2019/8/artificial-intelligence-in-higher-education-applications-promise-and-perils-and-ethical-questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Decision-Making Methods</title>
      <link>/post/group-decision-making-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/group-decision-making-methods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Delphi technique or method for group decision-making was formulated in the 1950s. Coming out of the Rand corporation, Helmer and Dalkey created the framework around the results of questionnaires sent out in rounds to experts on the subject pertaining to the needed decision (Rowe &amp;amp; Wright, 2001). The main advantage of the methodology is the aggregation of anonymous expert responses with response alterations. The main disadvantage is the lack of live real-time response and feedback (Twin, 2020).
The data and process of decision determinations from the Delphi technique is considered qualitative in nature do to the evaluation of opinions (Rowe &amp;amp; Wright, 2001). One other decision making technique for groups is based on qualitative data analysis is the Analytical Hierarchy Process (AHP) (Partovi, Burton, &amp;amp; Banerjee, 1990).
The AHP process involves the creation of a hierarchical relationship structure based on data from people or processes. This structure should represent the underlying decision making problem and the relationships should have pairwise values for descriptions. The creation of the hierarchical structure is similar to the Delphi technique of expert survey rounds but with more upfront emphasis on the focus of each level (Saaty, 1987). The key difference is the accumulation of the pairwise relationship weights or values between the nodes of the structure in AHP. This allows for the formulation of dominance matrices from which the analytical analysis can derive a decision making path for the solution (Saaty, 1987).
Finally, for more directed group decision making problems, quantitative processes can be formulated as novel solutions. Examples of this type of novel group decision making processes will translate systematic and qualitative data into quantitative sets using fuzzy logic systems (Sun, Wei, Wu, &amp;amp; Jing, 2020). The example from Sun, et al. (2020) illustrates the use of data from different organizations within an airport operations for group decisions regarding new and existing operational risks. The analysis will still use pairwise relationship matrices, as found in AHP, but with analytics focused on multi-criteria ranking and use of simulation models, for example Monte-Carlo, for statistical inferences that establish the decision solution (Sun, et al., 2020).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rowe, G., &amp;amp; Wright, G. (2001). Expert opinions in forecasting: The role of the delphi technique. &lt;i&gt;In Principles of Forecasting&lt;/i&gt; (2nd ed., Vol. 30, pp. 125–144). Boston, MA: Springer, Boston, MA. &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.1007/978-0-306-47630-3_7_&#34;&gt;http://doi.org/10.1007/978-0-306-47630-3_7_&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Partovi, F., Burton, J. &amp;amp; Banerjee, A. (1990), Application of analytical hierarchy process in operations management,&lt;i&gt; International Journal of Operations &amp;amp; Production Management &lt;/i&gt;, Vol. 10 No. 3, pp. 5-19. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi-org.proxy.cecybrary.com/10.1108/01443579010134945&#34;&gt;https://doi-org.proxy.cecybrary.com/10.1108/01443579010134945&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saaty, R. (1987). The analytic hierarchy process—what it is and how it is used. &lt;i&gt;Mathematical Modelling&lt;/i&gt;, 9(3-5), 161–176. &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.1016/0270-0255(87)90473-8&#34;&gt;http://doi.org/10.1016/0270-0255(87)90473-8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun, B., Wei, M., Wu, W., &amp;amp; Jing, B. B. (2020). A novel group decision making method for airport operational risk management. &lt;i&gt;Mathematical Biosciences and Engineering : MBE&lt;/i&gt;, 17(3), 2402–2417. &lt;a href=&#34;http://doi.org/10.3934/mbe.2020130&#34;&gt;http://doi.org/10.3934/mbe.2020130&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twin, A. (2020, March 6). &lt;i&gt;How the Delphi Method Works&lt;/i&gt;. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/delphi-method.asp&#34;&gt;https://www.investopedia.com/terms/d/delphi-method.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
